<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew Morycinski</title>
    <link>http://moryce.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matthew Morycinski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://moryce.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>http://moryce.ca/post/beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://moryce.ca/post/beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Grandpa&amp;rsquo;s typewriter was my first writing instrument. Using it had many advantages over scribbling. There was no need to learn to hold a pen, no risk of smearing. It even held paper for me. The resulting text was usually perfectly legible, as long as the reader overlooked a few words that were X-ed out. Of course, I had to learn to read first! – at least well enough to be able to recognize characters shown on keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this blog</title>
      <link>http://moryce.ca/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://moryce.ca/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Maciej (Matthew) Morycinski retired from being an industrial automation technologist, to pursue creative interests. Born in Poland, he now lives in Canada, in the province of British Columbia, city of Burnaby. His blog aims to entertain, educate, provoke reflection.
You can e-mail him at: m at tt dot moryce dot caThanks for reading!
Comments are not yet enabled. Please use the above email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http://moryce.ca/license/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://moryce.ca/license/license/</guid>
      <description>Creative writing content: Copyright © Maciej Morycinski, 2023.
Software content: generated by Hugo under Apache 2.0 License
Theme: Mainroad, a Hugo theme released under GPL V.2 License
Additional software content and styling is released under GPL V.2 License, quoted below:
 GNU GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE Version 2, June 1991 Copyright (C) 1989, 1991 Free Software Foundation, Inc. 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110-1301, USA Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies of this license document, but changing it is not allowed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Trivia</title>
      <link>http://moryce.ca/family-trivia/family-trivia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://moryce.ca/family-trivia/family-trivia/</guid>
      <description>My Mom&amp;rsquo;s great-grandfather—on her father&amp;rsquo;s father&amp;rsquo;s side—has set up the original Institute for Smallpox Vaccination in Warsaw, when Poland was still partitioned between Russia, Austria and Germany. It was a very successful family business, popular because the occupying power (Russia) did not provide a public vaccination service.
  My other Great-grandfather—on my maternal grandmother&amp;rsquo;s side—was Russian. He travelled to Russia during the 1917 Bolshevik Revolution, and subsequently died in one of Stalin&amp;rsquo;s purges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lem&#39;s Books</title>
      <link>http://moryce.ca/post/lems-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://moryce.ca/post/lems-books/</guid>
      <description>I always loved science-fiction. My favourite writer was a famous Polish author Stanisław Lem. He is not as well known in English-speaking countries, but many of his books were translated into multiple languages. One of his major novels, &amp;ldquo;Solaris,&amp;rdquo; was made into a movie on two occasions, first in the USSR by Tarkovsky (1972), and later in the USA by Sodebergh (2002). Unfortunately, their production values were much more solid than screenwriters&#39; understanding of Lem&amp;rsquo;s writing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
