<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Matthew Morycinski</title>
    <link>http://moryce.ca/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Matthew Morycinski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://moryce.ca/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual Life</title>
      <link>http://moryce.ca/post/spiritual-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://moryce.ca/post/spiritual-life/</guid>
      <description>Dear reader, I have a confession to make. Many years ago, I met a high school friend. Her name I will keep to myself. She was a strong, dare I say fanatical, believer in the Catholic religion. Once, in an emotional conversation, she simply said &amp;ldquo;God loves you Matthew!&amp;rdquo; It must have been said at the right time and place because the orbs of my inner world suddenly started to turn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lem&#39;s Books</title>
      <link>http://moryce.ca/post/lems-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://moryce.ca/post/lems-books/</guid>
      <description>As a young person, I loved science-fiction. My favourite writer was a famous Polish author Stanisław Lem. He is not as well known in English-speaking countries. However, many of his books were translated into multiple languages, including English. One of his novels, &amp;ldquo;Solaris,&amp;rdquo; was made into a movie, first in the USSR by Tarkovsky (1972), and later in the USA by Sodebergh (2002).&#xA;Lem was not entirely a science-fiction writer. He actually gave up writing in standard science-fiction genre quite early.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>http://moryce.ca/post/beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://moryce.ca/post/beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Grandpa&amp;rsquo;s typewriter was my first writing instrument. Using it had advantages over scribbling. There was no need to learn to hold a pen, no risk of smearing. It even held the paper for me. The resulting text was usually perfectly legible, as long as the reader overlooked a few words that were X-ed out. Of course, I had to learn to read first! – at least well enough to be able to recognize characters shown on keys.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
